《生活大爆炸》前情提要
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
莱纳德  跟大家说说你的新鲜事
So, Leonard, tell everyone your news.
我开始了一本书
Oh, uh, I am starting a book.
看书对佩妮来说才是大事吧
That would be big news from Penny,
但你以前应该已经读过书了啊
but you've read a book before.
他的意思是写书
He means he's writing a book.
是啊  这件事我想做很久了
I do. It's something I've been thinking about for a long time.
是在讲一个很聪明的物理学家
Yeah. It's about a brilliant physicist
用科学破案
who solves crimes using science.
莱纳德...
Oh, Leonard...
不是在写你
It's not about you!
-惨了  -怎么了
- Oh, boy. ?- What?
他们选出新的质子教授演员了
They cast the new Professor Proton.
-是谢尔顿吗  -不是
Is it Sheldon? Not exactly.
威尔
Wheaton!
是威尔·惠顿
It's Wil Wheaton.
时至今日
你在干嘛呢
Hey, what are you doing?
我还以为今晚要去莱纳德与佩妮家吃饭
I thought we were having dinner at Leonard and Penny's.
我才不去
Oh, no.
他们要看新版的《质子教授》
No, they're watching the new Professor Proton.
我无法阻止威尔·惠顿在网上出现
I-I can't keep Wil Wheaton off the Internet,
但我可以阻止他在我视网膜出现
but I can keep him off my retinas.
所以你要自己坐在这屁事不干吗
So, you're just gonna sit here by yourself and do nothing?
当然不是
Of course not.
我要去网上吐槽惠顿的节目  写他黑文
I'm going to write mean comments about Wil's show online.
你怎么可以没看过就吐槽人家节目
Well, you can't criticize something you haven't seen.
抱歉  您是第一天上网冲浪吗
I'm sorry, are you familiar with the Internet?
那如果我陪你一起看呢
Well, what if I watch it with you?
或许我也不喜欢这节目  我们可以一起吐槽
Maybe I won't like it and we can complain about it together.
自己找自己的吐槽题材好吗
Get your own thing to complain about.
你信我  我绝对有一个
Oh, trust me, I've got one.
你想  如果你看了
Look, at least if you watch it,
你就能找到更明确的吐槽点啊
maybe you can find more specific things to criticize.
这话有道理
Oh, that is a good point.
明确吐槽更能刀刀见血
Criticisms are more hurtful when they're specific.
♪ 拿起你的护目镜 ♪
? Grab your goggles ?
♪ 穿上你的实验服 ♪
? Lab coat on ?
《质子教授》
♪ 欢迎莅临  质子教授 ♪
? Here he comes, Professor Proton. ?
大家好  我是质子教授
Hey, everybody. I'm Professor Proton.
欢迎收看节目  今天我将教大家
Welcome to the show. Today I will be teaching you
用家庭常见物品来做真的气垫船
how to make a real hovercraft using common household items.
妈蛋  我的确喜欢能浮起来的东西
Darn it, I do like objects that hover.
你只需要一张光盘
All you will need is a CD,
一个瓶盖  一个气球  还有一些强力胶
a bottle cap, a balloon, and some super glue.
靠  这些东西我全有
Oh, no! I have all those things!
第十一季  第十五集
-我回来啦  -你回来啦
- Hey. - Hi.
那是什么声音
What's that noise?
是我的新键盘
Oh, it's my new keyboard.
看起来与听起来都像老式打字机
It looks and sounds like an old-fashioned typewriter.
让我感觉像个真小说家
It makes me feel like a real novelist.
你还给自己倒了杯威士忌啊
You poured yourself a Scotch.
是苹果汁
Apple juice.
没加糖
But unsweetened,
跟海明威当年爱喝的一样
like Hemingway used to drink. Ah.
-书写的怎么样了  -很好啊
- So, how's the book coming along? - Uh, good.
我刚写到了英雄主人翁罗根·迪恩
I just wrote the part where the hero,
这位牛逼的物理学家刚抵达欧洲核子研究中心
hotshot physicist Logan Dean, arrives at CERN.
他是以你为原型的吗
Oh, is he based on you?
算吧  不过可以吃乳制品
Uh, kind of. But he can eat dairy products
而不用担心有"排气"问题
without having to leave the room.
聪明  因为欧洲核子研究中心在瑞士
Yeah, that's smart, because CERN is in Switzerland
而那里出产很多起司
and there's a lot of cheese there.
相信我  这是之后一个伏笔呢
Uh, believe me, that is a plot point later.
等你写好之后  我很乐意拜读你的大作
Well, I'm excited to read it whenever you're ready.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想到谋杀工具要用什么了
Oh. Oh! I just thought of the murder weapon!
瑞士刀吗
Swiss army knife?
不是
No.
她这个强多了啊
That's way better.
看  真的行  我们成功了
Look, it works! We did it!
你看  留着那个光盘还是有用的
See, there was a reason to keep that TurboTax CD.
是啊
Yeah.
何止是光盘啊
A CD-ROM?
简直是"飞"盘啊
More like "CD-vroom."
你有没有一点难过你跟威尔·惠顿说
Do you feel bad you told Wil Wheaton
如果他出演这节目  你会跟他反目成仇
that you'd be his enemy if he did this show?
没  我难过的是
No. I feel bad
我跟一个会指出这件事的人订婚了
I'm engaged to somebody that would point that out.
现在到了质子教授的
It's time for Professor Proton's
每日科学笑话栏目
science joke of the day.
为什么你不能相信原子
Why can you not trust atoms?
因为它们组成[瞎掰]所有事物
Because they make up everything.
太好笑了
Oh, that's funny!
因为的确是啊  它们组成了所有事物
Yeah, because they do. They make up everything.
不知道是谁来了
Oh, I wonder who that could be.
我才以为这节目已经不能再赞了
Just when I thought this couldn't get any better,
威尔还给节目新增加了悬念
Wil has introduced suspense into the show.
是真正的太空总署宇航员  霍华德·沃罗威茨
Hey, it's real NASA astronaut, Howard Wolowitz!
什么
What?!
你好啊  质子教授
Hey, Professor Proton.
谢谢你的大驾光临
Hey, thanks for being here.
小事啦  我发射[午饭]休息时间刚好有空
No problem. I'm on my "launch" break.
威尔怎么可以邀请他上节目而不邀我
How could Wil ask Howard to be on his show and not me?
他的确是个宇航员啊
Well, he is an astronaut.
他也没有发动炒威尔鱿鱼的网上情愿
And he didn't start an online petition to get Wil fired.
那霍华德为什么不告诉我
But why wouldn't Howard tell me?
他大概是怕
Well, because he probably worried
你会像个小孩一样闹脾气吧
that you'd be a big baby about it.
听完这些答案仿佛醍醐灌顶
All those answers make a lot of sense.
谢谢你  艾米  我好多了
Thank you, Amy. That helps.
然后超级对撞机房的灯又再度亮起
And then, when the lights come back on in the supercollider room,
罗根·迪恩博士有两个重大发现
Dr. Logan Dean makes two important discoveries:
超胶子与谋杀案
a gluino and murder.
超胶子  有意思
Oh, gluino. That's exciting.
与谋杀案
And murder.
我听见了
I heard you.
第一次就听见了
The first time.
雷神扮演者和他弟弟都是帅哥猛男型演员
我不知道雷神兄弟俩谁会扮演罗根·迪恩
I don't know which Hemsworth is playing Logan Dean,
但我知道这角色超适合他俩
but I know it's a Hemsworth.
罗根的原型其实是我
Well, Logan's actually based on me.
头顶微秃其貌不扬的眼镜男演员
所以是年轻版的保罗·吉亚玛提
So a young Paul Giamatti.
我得先写完
Well, I have to finish writing it
才能被翻拍成电影啊
before they can make it into a movie,
我还有一些环节没弄明白
and I still have a few things to figure out.
你该跟伯纳黛特聊聊
You should talk to Bernadette.
因为她一直卧床休养  疯狂看了
Since she's been on bed rest, she's binged,
差不多世上每一档侦探剧吧
like, every detective show in the world.
印度有一档好玩的侦探剧叫《卡拉姆昌德》
Oh, there was a funny detective show in India called Karamchand.
他有名助手叫凯蒂
He had an assistant named Kitty,
他总是说"闭嘴  凯蒂"
and he was always saying, "Shut up, Kitty!"
其实没那么过分啦  如果你用印地语说
Sounds less mean if you say it in Hindi
而且不觉得女人也有感受的话
and don't think of women as having feelings.
你们好啊
Hello.
霍华德  我想告诉你我原谅你了
Howard, I want you to know that I forgive you.
我接受
I'll take it.
他原谅你什么
What's he forgiving you for?
不在乎  一切重新开始  祝我赎罪日快乐
Don't care. Clean slate. Happy Yom Kippur to me.
我知道你上了威尔的节目
I know that you were on Wil's show,
我也知道你为什么没告诉我
and I know why you didn't tell me.
是吗
Do you?
因为你害怕
Because you were afraid
我会找茬并对此事感到恼火
that I would be difficult and annoying about it.
我希望你的书也有像这样的惊喜转折
I hope your book has a twist as surprising as that.
并没有
It doesn't.
我还以为你要抵制威尔的节目
I thought you were boycotting Wil's show.
一开始是  但我决定试看一下
I was, but I decided to give it a shot,
结果我还看得挺开心的
and I actually enjoyed it.
好奇问一句  你怎么上的他节目
Just out of curiosity, how did you come to be on the show?
是他邀请你上  还是你要求上
Did he ask you? Did you ask him?
还是你恰好出现在拍摄现场按了门铃
Did you just show up on the set and ring that doorbell?
谢尔顿  如果你想上他的节目
Sheldon, if you want to be on the show,
你必须得先向威尔道歉
you're gonna have to apologize to Wil.
这样的确比较成熟
That would be the mature thing to do.
这个建议先记上  我们再想想别的
Let's put a pin in that and keep thinking.
什么什么  哪一部分
What? What? Which part?
胎动而已
That was just the baby kicking.
好吧
Got it.
-到目前为止都挺好  真不错  -是吗
- But this is good so far, really good. - Yeah?
是啊  我完全不知道谁是凶手
Yeah. I have no idea who the killer is.
太棒了  我也不知道
Oh, great. Me, neither.
佩妮知道你有个角色以她为原型吗
So, does Penny know you based a character on her?
什么角色
What character?
艾尔莎  研究中心的头儿  明显是佩妮啊
Ilsa, the head of the institute. That's clearly Penny.
不是
No, it's not.
是吗
Really?
自信  专挫男人锐气的美女
Confident, ball-busting beauty
还总是对罗根翻白眼
who's always rolling her eyes at Logan?
相信我  符合这描述的女人多了去了
Trust me, that describes more women than you think.
"他看着他的头儿  眼前这名绝色女子  低声说
"He looked at the stunning woman who was his boss and said..."
这是谋杀
It's murder.
这还用你说吗  天才
Figure that out yourself, genius?
好吧  没必要这么刻薄
Okay, no need to be snarky.
谁会想杀他
Who would want to kill him?
谁都有可能  西尔弗斯博士
Could be anyone. Dr. Silvers.
普利卡什博士
Dr. Prekash.
清洁工汉斯
Hans the janitor.
但门一直紧锁
But the door is locked,
所以肯定是这房间里的人干的
so it has to be someone in this room.
哇  你的推理真是棒棒哒
Wow, you are on fire.
或许是有点像佩妮
Maybe it is a little like Penny.
她有可能觉得高兴吗
Any chance she'll be flattered?
我不知道  她挺凶的
I don't know. She's pretty mean.
伊尔莎还是佩妮
Ilsa or Penny?
分不出吧
Exactly.
霍华德  有事吗
Oh, hey, Howard. What's up?
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
为何道歉
What for?
你好
Hello.
你好  谢尔顿
Hello, Sheldon.
我猜你来这里是要告诉我
I suppose you've come here to tell me
你把我升级到了你的头号秘密仇家名单
that you've moved me to your super secret enemies list.
我没有什么头号秘密仇家名单
I don't have a super secret enemies list.
我不是邦德电影里的坏蛋
I'm not a Bond villain.
我只是一名普通人
I'm just a regular guy,
拥有一份普通的仇家名单
with a regular enemies list.
顺便说一声  你不在名单内了
Which, by the way, you are no longer on.
是吗  那的确了不得
Really? Well, that is something.
虽然我不在乎  但的确了不得
It's not something that I care about, but it is something.
他是想说他很抱歉
He's trying to say he's sorry.
是的
I am.
我看了你的节目  真的很棒
I watched your show, and it's really good.
谢谢
Aw, thank you.
我后悔曾对你那么过分
And I regret how hard I was on you.
我想告诉你
I want you to know
能上《质子教授》这个节目
that being on the Professor Proton show
一直是我儿时的梦想
has been a childhood dream of mine.
所以如果你以后还想找嘉宾科学家
So, if you're ever looking for any more scientist guests,
我希望你能考虑一下我
I hope you'll consider me.
感谢你这番话  谢尔顿  我会记得你想来
I appreciate that, Sheldon, and I'll keep it in mind.
其实呢...
You know, actually...
太好了
Yay!
不不  我的节目
No. No. I want to have
希望有更多的女性科学家加入
more female scientists represented on the show,
我刚想  艾米会不会有兴趣来啊
and I thought maybe Amy might be interested?
或者...
Or...
这样不是更好吗
wouldn't it be nice
让我们俩一起上节目  告诉大家
to have us both on, to show that
就算女科学家也能找到男朋友
even female scientists can land a man?
我已经道过歉了
I said "Sorry."
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
我好喜欢  我等不及想知道凶手是谁了
I like it. I can't wait to see who the killer is.
是艾尔莎那妞吗  感觉她蛮凶的
Is it that Ilsa girl? She seems pretty mean.
是可爱的那种凶
But adorably mean,
就像小狮子宝宝一样
like a baby lion?
不  正常的凶  就像正常狮子
No, regular mean, like a regular lion.
但考虑到这个角色的原型  描写还是很准确的
But it seems pretty accurate, considering who you based it on.
你觉得原型是谁呢
And who do you think that is?
但这门一直紧锁
But the door is locked,
所以肯定是这房间里的人干的
so it has to be someone in this room.
哇  你的推理真是棒棒哒
Wow. You are on fire.
哦  你...
Oh. Y...
博纳黛特  没错
Bernadette. Yeah, sure.
你们俩都有作案动机
Each one of you had a motive.
是谁死了  轮得到你小子来当侦探
Who died and made you detective?
他死了
He did.
我想你忘了你自己也有动机
I think you're neglecting your own motive,
你那巨大的自卑情结
a massive inferiority complex.
才没那么大呢
It's not massive.
也就是中等大小吧
It's just average-sized.
无意打扰你们  但有人把血踩得到处都是
I don't mean to interrupt, but somebody's tracking
所以...  算了  是我踩的
blood everywhere, so-- never mind, it's me.
你把我们都列为嫌疑人
You say we're all suspects.
我们怎么知道你不是凶手呢
How do we know you're not the killer?
我有不在场证明
I have an alibi.
没错  他还没有聪明到能策划一场谋杀
Yeah. He's not smart enough to pull off a murder like this.
这太明显了  金发  刻薄  戴眼镜
It's pretty obvious: blonde, mean, glasses.
-我这里面没写戴眼镜  -真的吗
- It doesn't say "glasses." - Oh, really?
后面会加上的  因为艾尔莎是戴眼镜的
But it will, because Ilsa does.
你知道还有谁戴吗
And you know who else wears them?
博纳黛特
Bernadette.
原型就是她  是的
And-and that's her, cause it's,
完完全全  就是她
it's totally, it's totally her.
艾米  太好了  你在家
Oh, Amy. Good, you're here.
怎么了
Hi. What's up?
你愿意上电视吗
How would you like to be on television?
是要我上新闻
Is it gonna be a news story
说你平日个性低调  不与人来往
where I have to say you were quiet and kept to yourself
我和其他人一样感到震惊吗
and I'm as shocked as anyone?
不  不是的
No, it's not.
威尔·威顿想请你上他的《质子教授》节目
Wil Wheaton wants you to be on Professor Proton.
谢谢  不过我不感兴趣
That's nice, but I'm not really interested.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
可是他想要采访从事科学事业的女性
But he wants to talk about women in science.
你是女人  又从事科学事业  上啊妹子
You're a woman, you're in science. You go, girl.
我很支持女性从事科学事业
I'm all for promoting women in science,
但我真的不想上威尔的节目
but I don't really want to be on Wil's show.
是因为里面可能有小孩吗
Is it because kids may be there,
而小孩又是头虱常见携带者  我懂你
and they're known carriers of head lice? I get that.
好吧  就当是这样吧
Sure, that's the reason.
等等
Wait a minute.
你常常炫耀说头虱不会对你有兴趣
You're always bragging that lice aren't attracted to you
因为你头皮油得不行
because your scalp is so oily.
你还把它写在约会介绍上了
That was on your dating profile.
好吧  我说
Okay, look,
我知道你对《质子教授》这节目有很深的感情
I know you have strong feelings about Professor Proton,
我不想掺和进这事情
and I don't want to get in the middle of that.
所以你会因为我可能不高兴
So you're not going to do something
就不去做某一些事情吗
just because you think it might upset me?
这问题很微妙
Well, it's tricky,
因为诚实回答这个问题
because answering that question honestly
就是一个我担心你会不高兴而不想做的事
is one of the things I tend not to do because it upsets you.
好吧  人家现在不开心了
Well, that's very upsetting.
我不是说了吗
Like I said.
你还有哪些事是因为我而不去做的
What other things don't you do because of me?
还记得上周我们去那家
Remember last week when we went to
我很喜欢的斗琴酒吧吗
that dueling piano bar I was so excited about?
-不记得去过  -开始领会到了吗
- No. - Well, now you're getting it.
乖乖  真不知道那些没有卧床静养的人
Boy, I don't know how people who aren't on bed rest
怎么有办法"与卡戴珊一家同行"
keep up with the Kardashians.
有时候你只好在车里读八卦
Well, sometimes you have to read in your car
然后告诉丈夫你下班晚了
while your husband thinks you're working late.
说到这事  他昨天给我看他的书了
Speaking of which, he came by yesterday to show me his book.
你觉得如何
Oh, and-and what did you think?
我很喜欢呀
I liked it.
真的吗  艾尔莎这个角色不会惹到你吗
Really? The Ilsa character didn't bother you?
他只是写书夸张化了  你一点都不像她
Oh, he was exaggerating. You're not really like that.
我知道我不像她
Well, I know I'm not like that.
那个角色的原型是你
The character was based on you.
我不知道该怎么告诉你
I don't know what to tell you.
我给莱纳德提这事时  他说原型是你
When I brought it up with Leonard, he said it was you.
我给他提这事时  他...
Well, when I brought it up, he...
立马举止诡异  然后溜了
got all squirrelly and left the room.
奶奶个腿的
Son of a bitch.
我刚知道了一件很难过的事
I just learned some very distressing news.
有时候  艾米因为担心我的反应
Sometimes, Amy doesn't do things
而刻意不去做一些事
because she's worried about how I'll react.
首先  不是有时候  而是一贯如此
First of all, it's not sometimes, it's always.
第二  不光是艾米  而是每个人
Second, it's not Amy, it's everybody.
第三  这不是新事  这众所周知
And third, it's not news, it's well-established.
没错  就像我本来想买牛角包[法语]吃
Yeah. Like just now I wanted to get a croissant,
但我不想听到你说"乌拉拉"[法语表惊讶]
but I didn't want to hear you say, "Ooh, la, la."
所以你说每个人都如履薄冰
So you're saying everyone walks on eggshells
来保护我的情绪吗
to spare my feelings?
不  当然不是  因为我们可不想
No, of course not, because we don't want
听到你抱怨我们把冰踩碎的声音
to hear you complain about how much you hate the sound
有多讨厌
of crunching eggshells.
我不希望和艾米的关系变成这样
I don't want my relationship with Amy to be like that.
谢尔顿  艾米清楚会变成这样
Sheldon, Amy knew what she was getting into.
真的吗
You think?
真的  我们警告过她
Yes, we warned her.
无论如何  我还可以改
Well, regardless, I can change.
-好吧  -你当然可以啦
- Sure. - Yeah, of course you can.
每个人都以为自己很了解我
You know, everybody thinks I'm so predictable.
明天上班时
Well, tomorrow I'm gonna show up at work
我要做一些谁都猜不到的事
and do something no one will expect.
反戴棒球帽以证明你的论点吗
Wear a baseball cap backwards to prove your point?
没错  但是哪顶帽子呢
Yes, but which hat?
格兰芬多
Gryffindor.
好吧  既然你猜到了  我就不戴了
Well, now that you guessed it, I'm not gonna do it.
不  你会戴的
Yeah, you will.
是啦
Yeah.
看来子弹直接打穿过去了
Looks like the bullet went right through you.
靠  罗根  你何时才能知难而退
Damn it, Logan. When are you gonna stop?
抱歉  我得到的并不是放弃学博士
Sorry. I didn't get my PhD in quitting.
你只是个物理学家  凭什么觉得自己能侦破罪案
You're a physicist. What makes you think you can solve a crime?
他失了很多血
He's losing a lot of blood.
太好了  我又得清理了
Great. I'm gonna have to clean that up.
你知道吗  用一点苏打水就能洗净血渍
You know what? A little soda water might get that right out.
-我们得找些绷带  -不
- We got to find some bandages. - No.
没时间了
There's no time.
痛吗
Does it hurt?
你所做的一切都令我痛
Everything you do hurts.
那你为何一直来找虐
Then why do you keep coming back for more?
在你眼中我就是这样子的吗
So this is what you think of me?
我很凶  我所做的一切都令你痛
Huh? I'm mean and everything I do hurts you?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我知道我是艾尔莎
I know I'm Ilsa.
什...  说什么傻话
Wha...? That is crazy.
你们俩截然不同
You-you two are totally different.
怎么个不同
How?
你...  她...
Well, you... She...
她叫艾尔莎啊
Her name's Ilsa.
来来来
You know what?
无所谓  随你怎么写
It's fine. Write whatever you want.
顺便说一下  罗根·迪恩可以自称身高172
And by the way, Logan Dean can tell everyone he's five-eight,
但鬼才相信呢
but he's not fooling anybody!
你确定要走这一步吗
Are you sure that's the move you want to make?
当然
Absolutely.
好吧
Okay.
将军
Checkmate.
我真没料到会这样
Oh, I did not see that coming.
棋高一着啊  艾米
That's well played, Amy.
怎么回事
What's going on?
你赢了我  我回以谦逊和钦佩
You beat me, and I am responding with humility and admiration.
不然你觉得是什么
What does it look like?
你故意让我赢的
You let me win so you could show me
好让我看到你在情感上有多成熟  对不对
how emotionally mature you are, didn't you?
我等不到你凭实力赢我啊
Well, I couldn't wait for you to actually beat me;
那得等到天荒地老
that would take forever.
对不起
I'm sorry. It's...
我想让你看到
I'm trying to show you
我能改变
that I can change.
我不希望你为了我错过想做的事情
I-I don't want you to miss out on things because of me.
我知道
I know you don't.
还有  也许在世上某处
You know, and maybe somewhere out there,
有个小女孩看到你上威尔的节目后
there is a little girl who will see you on Wil's show
意识到自己长大后
and realize that she, too, can grow up
也可以变成如此聪明  有才
to be a brilliant, amazing,
成功的科学家
successful scientist.
谢谢
Thank you.
尽管她象棋下得超烂
Who is really terrible at chess.
知道了
Got it.
不不  我是说烂出新境界
No, no, no. I mean really bad.
你的皇后在那干嘛呢  逛大街吗
What was your queen doing over there, going shopping?
我不是有意把佩妮写进去的
I mean, I-I didn't intend to write about Penny,
但也许我潜意识地这么做了
but I guess maybe subconsciously I did.
你是想说"无意识地"吧  亲爱的
I believe you mean "unconsciously" dear.
对啦  要是你不总是纠正我
Yeah, sure. You know, it would be nice
那就最好不过了
if you didn't correct me all the time.
要是你没地方被纠正  那也挺好的
It would be nice if I didn't have to.
也许你写这本书是个坏主意
Maybe this book of yours is a bad idea.
此话怎讲
What do you mean?
你只是个物理学家
Well, you're a physicist.
凭什么觉得自己能写书
What makes you think you can write a book?
你只是个物理学家
You're a physicist.
凭什么觉得自己能侦破罪案
What makes you think you can solve a crime?
我需告辞了
Got to go.
应该是我"得"
I think you mean "Have..."
佩妮  好消息
Oh, Penny, good news.
-那不是你  -什么
- It's not you. - What?
艾尔莎  不是你  是我妈
Ilsa. It's not you. It's my mother.
原来我一直在写我妈
I've been writing about my mother!
我想你忘了你自己也有动机
I think you're neglecting your own motive,
你那巨大的自卑情结
a massive inferiority complex.
才没那么大呢
It's not massive.
也就是中等大小吧
It's just average-sized.
我们得找些绷带
We got to find some bandages.
没时间了
There's no time.
痛吗
Does it hurt?
你所做的一切都令我痛
Everything you do hurts.
那你为何一直来找虐
Then why do you keep coming back for more?
也许你喜欢这种感觉
Maybe you like it.
可能真是这样
I-- M-Maybe I do.
我只不过是个物理学家  我写个毛书啊
You know what? I'm a physicist. What am I doing writing a book?
今天的节目就要到此为止了
Well, that is our show for today.
我想特别向艾米·福勒博士道谢
And I want to say a very special thank you
感谢您的光临
to Dr. Amy Fowler for being here.
能邀请到你  我们感到十分开心
It was a real pleasure having you.
你能感受到那份开心
And you can feel that pleasure
因为你的伏核里没有病变
because you don't have a lesion in your nucleus accumbens.
真心希望我没有
I really hope I don't.
好啦  下次见
All right, we'll see you next time!
艾米
Amy.
你简直在发光
You were glowing.
因为头皮很油啦
Oily scalp.
我真以你为傲
I'm so proud of you.
我也以你为傲
And I'm proud of you.
因为你看不出我有多妒忌吗
Because you can't tell how jealous I am?
不不  我看得出来
No, no, no. I can.
我能看出你忍得有多辛苦
I can tell how hard you're trying to keep it in.
忍到内伤
Really hard.
我去睡了
I'm gonna go to bed.
好的  我去屋顶上大叫发泄了
All right. I'm gonna go scream on the roof.
-爱你哦  -爱你哦
- Love you. - Love you.